

#### **CONTACT INFO**

- Pangalore, India
- arun.srinivasan@outlook.in
- +91 81237 61771
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/c4arun/
- https://srinivasan-arun.github.io/cv/

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

**Engineering Management** 

Software Development

**Process Improvement** 

Resource Planning

Tech Design

Microservices

**Event-Driven Architecture** 

#### Cloud

- AWS
- GCP

#### DevOps

- Jenkins
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- ELK
- App Monitoring Tools
  - Grafana, Prometheu

## Full Stack Web Development

- Angular
- ReactJS (Micro Front-Ends)
- Java/JEE
- Spring Boot
- Vert.X
- PWA
- NodeJS
- Elastic Search
- MySQL, MongoDB
- Apache Kafka
- Redis

#### Tools

- JIRA
- Git
- Confluence
- Bitbucket

# **ARUN SRINIVASAN**

# ENGINEERING MANAGER

#### SUMMARY

Engineering Manager having 10+ years of experience in IT industry. I act as an intermediary between the business and technical teams to understand business requirements, define the technical architecture and support development teams with implementation and drive engineering excellence by improving processes around DevOps, Agile. Committed to efficiently completing projects by leveraging available engineering talent.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Engineering Manager**

Flipkart | Mar 2022 - present

- Led cross-functional teams of 12 software developers to deliver high-quality products on time and within budget
- Successfully led the team through Co-Branded Credit Card project that involved integrating multiple systems and technologies, resulting in a successful launch of the project and positive customer feedback.
- Led the development API Gateway, Scheduler and Recon as Platforms.

# **Engineering Manager**

BetterPlace | Apr 2019 - Mar 2022

- Bootstrapped the next-gen Platform 2.0 approach for all products with the aim to move towards a SaaS-based business model.
- Handled migration of a complex monolith application to highly scalable event-driven micro-services based product model.
- Conduct day-to-day project coordination, planning, and implementation across multiple teams.
- Translated requirements into polished, high-level designs
- Implemented and improved processes around DevOps, Agile and ensured high-quality product delivery within the given timeline.
- Recruit, Coach, Mentor, Motivate and Lead a team of Engineers.
- Be a champion of engineering excellence establish team metrics for measurement of engineering and operational excellence. Implement a consistent, regular process for assessment and improvement

## **Application Team Lead**

Unisys India | Jul 2012 - Mar 2019

- Worked on many complex web projects from the scratch majorly in Public-Sector and Transportation Domain.
- Hands-on experience in implementing IoT-based solution.
- Hands-on experience on complex Java/JEE, NodeJS based web development

## EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

## Coimbatore Institute of Technology, Anna University

B.E in Computer Science | Jun 2008 - Apr 2012

• CGPA 8.56

## S.K.V Higher Secondary School, TamilNadu

Higher Secondary Education | Jun 2006 - Apr 2008

• Percentage - 95%